Runa from the House of Sasaki
佐佐木家的瑠奈
was raised by an overprotective mother,
有过度保护的妈妈
a kind father,
温柔的爸爸
and an older brother
以及总会率先行动
who did everything for her in advance.
负责处理大小事的哥哥
She was the butterfly, the flower, of the family.
让她成为娇生惯养的女孩
She was especially fond
她最喜欢开在家里附近
of the chocolate donuts made by the neighborhood donut shop,
甜甜圈老店的巧克力甜甜圈
online video games,
还有拿手的在线游戏
and her friendly gaming companions.
以及总是很贴心的游戏网友
But as for unfamiliar places,
陌生的地方
unfamiliar things,
和陌生的事物
and unfamiliar people…
还有不认识的陌生人…
she hates those.
她都讨厌
ORIGINAL STORY BY MASHIRO
（原作：Mashiro）
Spoiled from birth, Runa of the House of Sasaki
在溺爱中长大的佐佐木瑠奈
believes that if she waits quietly,
觉得只要静静地装模作样
someone will give her attention.
就会有人贴心地对待自己
SILENCE
（不理睬）
The other girls in class
班上的女生
find her difficult to handle.
都不晓得如何和她相处
THAT GIRL IS KIND OF HARD TO APPROACH
（那个女生感觉好难接近）
At one time, the older girls bullied her…
以前也有高年级生霸凌过她
THOSE RIBBONS ARE HUGE. WHO DOES SHE THINK SHE IS?
（有够跩，蝴蝶结太大了吧）
But Runa has 300 friends online
不过瑠奈认识300个网友
so paid it no mind.
她一点也不在意
-RUNA, ARE YOU OKAY? -JUST IGNORE THEM
（被霸凌了）
Even when a girl in the same class
就算国中三年以来
for all three years of junior high…
同班的女生…
Sasaki, you have class duty today, right?
佐佐木同学，你今天是值日生吧
Shouldn't you erase the board?
你不去擦黑板吗？
Oh, right.
我都忘了
…still calls her by her last name,
现在仍用姓氏称呼她
Runa pays it no mind.
但瑠奈一点也不在意
On top of that, Runa of the House of Sasaki
不过佐佐木家的瑠奈
has always been very pretty,
从以前就是惊世美少女
and many boys have harbored secret crushes on her.
有很多男生默默暗恋她
But on school trips, when they catch sight
但是她参加学校活动时的便服
of her frilly Lolita-style street clothes,
却是彻头彻尾的洛丽塔打扮
they can't help but compare her to other girls
和其他女生的风格不太一样
and stop short of talking to her.
让男生不太敢接近她
SOMETHING'S DIFFERENT ABOUT HER.
（总觉得和印象不同…）
In addition, Runa's older brother is quite handsome,
而且瑠奈的哥哥是个帅哥
and an older friend from childhood
从小认识的友人哥哥
is even more handsome.
也是突破天际的帅
With these two as her standard,
这两人成了她看男生的基准
the boys in her class all appear to her like this.
自然地，她觉得班上男生都长这样
Hey, look!
欸，你看
We made a new video.
我拍了新视频
That's so cute!
超可爱的
I did it with Yuka.
我和由佳一起跳的
Will you dance for me too?
你也来跳跳看
Sure.
好啊
First, you go like this…
首先是这样
Are you serious?
那是什么啊？
-GIRLS IN MY CLASS DID A FUNNY DANCE -BUT I'LL BET YOU DIDN'T JOIN THEM
（教室里有女生在跳奇怪的舞）
-RUNA HAS PROBLEMS COMMUNICATING -JUST ASK THEM TO LET YOU JOIN IN!
（瑠奈很不会沟通耶 叫她们让你加入就好啦！）
Oh no, I'll be late!
糟糕，要迟到了
A-chan, Mako-rin, bye-bye!
小敦，真真，拜拜
Mi-chan, bye-bye!
小美拜拜
You too, Sasaki. Bye-bye!
佐佐木同学也拜拜
Have fun!
加油哦
Of course!
讨厌啦
Runa of the House of Sasaki…
佐佐木家的瑠奈…
…always gets her way at home
个性内向又任性
but outside, she's very much a coward.
是个超级胆小鬼
Coming!
来了
But these days, Runa…
最近的瑠奈…
Hi there, Runa!
瑠奈，欢迎你
Has gained an older female friend.
交到了相对年长的女性朋友
I bought the new pudding variety from the convenience store.
我买了超商新推出的布丁哦
Akane is a bit more adult than the girls in her class.
茜比班上女生还要年长一点
Akane!
茜
I saw a funny dance today at school.
我今天在学校看到奇怪的舞
Oh yeah? Show me.
那是什么？跳给我看
Even if Runa is mean or selfish,
即使瑠奈恶作剧或耍任性
Akane remains kind,
她也愿意和瑠奈做朋友
and Runa has the slightest feeling
所以瑠奈多少有察觉到
that it's not a friendship of equals.
彼此之间不算是对等关系
Oh, and that's not all--
还有哦，还有哦
Hang on a second.
等我一下
A friend is texting me.
有朋友传信息来
HUH? WHAT IS IT?
（是什么呢？我看看）
Even so,
但茜这个人
Akane is not family or a childhood friend,
不是她的家人或儿时玩伴
so things don't go exactly as she would like.
不一定会照瑠奈的意思行动
Another friend?
其他朋友…
Why can't she reply later?
信息晚点再看不就好了？
I'm with her right now.
明明和瑠奈待在一起
When Runa's mood darkens,
即使瑠奈不高兴
Akane doesn't go out of her way to cheer her up.
茜也不会随时随地安慰她
Actually, she doesn't even notice.
甚至是完全没发现
Hey, Runa! Look!
欸，瑠奈，你看这个
They're shooting a drama near the station
现在车站前有剧组在拍连续剧
and that actor Sato is there! Let's go see him!
那个演员佐藤在现场耶 要不要去看？
Akane, your tastes are pretty trendy.
茜还蛮爱跟风的吧？
That's right. They are.
没错，我就是这种人
AND BUYS THE LATEST PRODUCTS
（喜欢明星艺人，也爱买新商品）
However…
但是…
Hurry!
快点…
Wait for me!
等一下啦
The new thrills she experiences
跟哥哥他们相处起来
differ from
不太一样
her brother's friends.
有另一种新的兴奋感
Even though Runa supposedly hates
陌生的事物和陌生人
new people and new things.
明明以前都很讨厌…
Sato was pretty hot from afar too.
远远欣赏的佐藤也好帅哦
You think?
是吗？
Isn't Yamada more handsome?
山田比他更帅吧？
Yeah, but…
是没错啦
Yamada is Yamada.
但是山田是山田啊
You have a point.
也是啦
Hey, look! Over there!
你看那边
They're dancing!
有人在跳舞
It looks fun!
好好玩的样子
I don't get people who dance in the street.
瑠奈不懂在路边跳舞哪里好玩
Why don't we join in
我们要不要
with that funny dance you showed me?
也去跳一下那种怪舞？
Absolutely not!
绝对不要
Was it like this?
是像这样？
No, like this!
是这样啦
Still, these days…
但是最近
she's started to feel
她开始觉得
that having more friends to do funny dances with
如果有更多能一起跳怪舞的朋友
might be nice.
或许会更开心
I need a good romance.
好想谈恋爱啊
My life plan calls for marriage
在小桃我的人生蓝图中
around the time I graduate college.
本来预计在大学毕业时就结婚
My mom had me at 20 years old.
我妈也是在20岁时生下我
I always thought I'd do it while I am young as possible.
所以小桃我也想趁年轻生小孩
But for that, I need a husband first.
但是首先要有个老公嘛
And to get a husband, I need a boyfriend first.
要有老公，必须先交男友嘛
So I need romance--
所以我才想要谈恋爱…
Wait,
等等
let the attacker make the final blow.
最后一击交给输出
Yeah, just a bit more.
对，再一下就好
I did it! Quest cleared!
万岁！完成任务！
Don't tell me neither of you were listening?
难不成现在没人在听我说话？
Oh, sorry.
抱歉，欸，小桃
Look, Momo! I reached level 50 in a week.
我在这一星期就升到50等了
Who cares?!
没兴趣
If you do as I tell you,
只要照着瑠奈说的做
you'll max out before the end of the month.
这个月内就能满等哦
Akane…
我说茜
You're spending a free afternoon
难得悠闲的下午
playing games with a runaway middle school student.
却和逃家初中生狂玩在线游戏
Are you okay?
这样没问题吗？
She's not a runaway!
她才没有逃家啦
She's just having a cold war with her older brother
但她现在和哥哥冷战中
and doesn't want to be at home.
在家里待不下去的样子
That's no reason that the two of us
就算如此，我们窝在这
should have to play around with a child.
陪小孩玩在线游戏真的没问题吗？
If you're so bored, why don't you go home?
如果嫌无聊，你可以先回去啊
You had no reason to come anyway.
是你自己没事跑来这里的
Silence!
给我闭嘴
Don't test me, little girl.
少瞧不起人了，小鬼
I envy you, Akane.
真羡慕茜
Meeting a hot younger guy by chance…
突然就认识年纪小的帅哥
You mean Yamada?
你说山田吗？
You've got the wrong idea.
你误会了啦
Oh, but we have gotten a little closer.
不过最近我们有变得比较要好
He added me to his friend list.
还同意我的好友申请
ADD YOU AS A FRIEND? SURE.
（好友申请？可以啊）
Though he's as expressionless as ever
虽然他还是一样冷淡
and won't go hunting with me.
也不愿意和我去打怪
The gap in levels is too big.
因为茜的等级差太多
There's no incentive for him.
对山田来说没好处
But if I ask, he tells me all about different equipment.
但只要问他，就会教我装备之类的
He's surprisingly kind.
其实意外的亲切啦
Surprisingly? He's always been kind.
意外？他从以前就待人很亲切啊
He still tutors me,
像现在也是，他明明也是考生
even though he's studying for entrance exams.
却还是愿意来教瑠奈读书
Huh? Then he must be popular with girls.
真的啊？那他一定很受欢迎吧？
Super popular.
超受欢迎的
I guess he isn't into girls.
不知道他是不是怕女生
I've never seen him with a girlfriend.
从来没看过像是女友的人
Huh? What a waste!
真可惜
Maybe I can change his mind.
小桃我来当女友候选吧
Speak of the devil…
说山田，山田到
SYSTEM: YAMADA HAS LOGGED IN
（山田上线了）
Hey there, Yamada!
喂，山田！
Hi.
你好
I haven't seen you online for a while.
好久没看到山田上线了
I guess.
是啊
I've been busy lately.
我最近比较忙
Oh, that's right!
对了
I tried the method you taught me
我用了你上次教我的方法
and buffed my footwear.
试着强化了鞋子
I THINK YOU USED THE WRONG MATERIAL.
（你是不是搞错强化材料了？）
Huh? I needed to use the INT jewel, right?
只要加上INT石就行了吧？
I copied what you did.
我是学山田的做法
I'm a wizard, so I need INT.
我是魔职才会用INT石
But a Paladin needs VIT more.
圣骑士应该首选VIT石才对
You mean I used the wrong jewel?
不能用这种宝石吗？
999 FRAGMENTS FORM ONE JEWEL…
（999个宝石碎片 才能合成1个宝石）
I worked hard to gather the fragments.
亏人家还努力收集了
Would you like to use my backup footwear?
要用我别只角色的鞋子吗？
I have some with max shielding power.
我有给盾职用的，已经强化完的鞋子
No, it's fine.
不，没关系
I just need to form a VIT jewel, right?
只要收集VIT石就好吧
I'll go hunting again until I get enough fragments.
我再重新去打怪收集
I know where my effort is needed now.
反正我也记得哪里会掉宝了
Right…
也是
Sorry, I was out of line.
抱歉，我说了多余的话
Please do your best.
请努力强化装备吧
A smiley face?!
笑脸贴图？
How rare…
真难得
She's shouting to herself.
一个人大叫
Has she finally gone nuts?
她终于坏掉了吗？
Sounds like she's having fun.
好像很开心
This is so boring!
好无聊！
All you do is play online games!
茜一直在玩游戏，真无聊
I wanna go out! I want a blind date!
我想去外面！想要联谊！
Why don't you try it too, Momo?
小桃要不要也玩玩看？
It's actually quite fun.
还蛮有趣的哦
I'm allergic to that stuff.
小桃我不会玩那个
Don't be like that.
别那么说
I don't know anything about computers!
人家又不懂电脑
Get used to it, and it's a piece of cake.
只要习惯，操作也很简单哦
I'm about to go hunting,
我现在要去打怪
so why don't you watch?
你看一下吧
Um, I don't know much about computers,
虽然小桃我不太懂电脑
but I imagine smoke is a bad sign.
冒烟是代表出事了吧？
Akane's PC broke?
Akane的电脑坏掉了？
Yeah.
嗯
It blew up while she was playing online.
好像在游戏途中爆炸了
FOS has gotten more demanding since the last update.
FOS前阵子更新后，就容易跑不动
Maybe it was too much for her hardware.
大概是系统负荷太重了吧
She can't play until she gets money for a new one.
说在存钱买新电脑前，无法玩游戏
She was really sad.
她现在超沮丧
NO EYE CONTACT DUE TO COLD WAR
（冷战中不肯面对面说话）
HMM…
（嗯…）
JOB WANTED ADS
（《打工情报志》）
Coming!
来了
Who's there?
是哪位…
Hi.
你好
I brought a repairman.
我带修理业者
See?
来了唷
EITA SASAKI CALLING
（佐佐木瑛太来电）
-Yeah? -Good morning, Yamada-kun!
-喂 -山田，早啊
Hi…
早…
What is it?
有事吗？
Do you happen to have a used computer?
你手边有没有旧电脑？
An older model perhaps.
例如以前用过的
Nope.
没有
It seems Akane's PC broke.
Akane的电脑好像坏了
They say smoke came out.
听说还冒烟的样子
Smoke? From where?
冒烟…是从哪里？
I haven't seen it, so who knows.
我没实际看到，不晓得
When you have time,
你有空的时候
would you mind taking a look for her?
可以去看看Akane的电脑吗？
Me?
我去吗？
You might be able to fix it with spare parts.
说不定只要换零件就能修好
Shouldn't you do it?
你去就行了吧？
I could do it,
我去也可以啦
but it'd be bad if I made a mistake, right?
但有什么万一就糟了吧
Plus, a virile young man entering the apartment of a cute female college student
健康男子进入可爱女大学生的房间
sounds kind of dangerous.
其实蛮危险的
What the heck am I, then?
你把我当成什么了？
A new species.
新物种
Runa said she was really sad.
瑠奈说Akane变得好沮丧
Akane has been trying really hard at FOS lately.
说她最近很认真在玩FOS
I feel bad for her.
看起来好可怜
Why not stop by after tutoring Runa?
你当完瑠奈的家教回家顺路去看吧
I'll have Runa show you the way to her apartment. Okay?
瑠奈会负责带你去Akane家
Please.
求求你了
No, it's fine.
不，没关系
I just need to get the VIT jewel, right?
只要收集VIT石就好吧
I'll go hunting again until I get enough fragments.
我再重新去打怪收集
You came to repair my computer, Yamada?
山田来帮我修电脑吗？
That's right! I brought him!
是啊！是瑠奈带他来的
I just came to have a look. Don't expect too much.
我只是来看看，你不用抱太多期待
Runa brought him!
是瑠奈哦
Don't look at me like that.
不要用那种眼神看我
-I don't know if I can fix it. -Runa--
-我不保证能修好 -是瑠奈…
A laptop, huh?
是笔电啊
Make yourselves at home.
放轻松坐吧
Would you like some snacks?
你们要不要吃零食？
-No need. -Please!
-不用顾虑我… -我要吃！
Yamada's a good guy.
山田真是好人
Hey, Akane!
茜…
Yeah?
嗯？
Um, over there in that room…
就是那边的房间…
The "you know what"…
挂在那里
Is it okay?
没关系吗？
Thank god. He didn't notice.
太好了，他没发现
Well, it's Yamada. Maybe he's immune.
反正山田也不在乎吧
It feels a little strange for Yamada to be in my apartment,
看到山田在自己家里，虽然有点奇妙
but then Runa said…
但瑠奈之前也说了
Yamada's not into girls.
山田怕女生
If I make too big a deal,
要是我的举动不自然
it'll be uncomfortable for him.
山田也会不自在吧
Just act normal!
保持平常心吧
Have you two eaten lunch?
你们已经吃过午餐了吗？
If not, I'll fix up something simple.
如果还没，我就简单做一下
I want some!
我要吃！
What about you, Yamada?
山田要不要也吃一点？
Thanks, I'll have some.
好，我要吃
Oh, how rare.
哎呀，真难得
ASSUMED HE WASN'T HUNGRY
（本来猜他会说“我不饿”）
It's fine.
不用了
I'm a bit late in saying this, but…
我之前忘了说
Yeah?
嗯？
The curry you made
上次的咖喱
was really good.
非常好吃
Sorry, I only remembered now, so I forgot
抱歉，我现在才想起来
to bring the containers.
我忘记还你保鲜盒了
I'm glad!
我好高兴
I'll make something special,
我会卯足全力下厨的
so eat all you want.
要尽量吃哦
Oh, about the guild…
话说公会
A new girl joined.
新加入了一个女生
She's really open-hearted and cute.
她的个性很老实，超可爱的
Princess Ruri!
瑠璃姬
I got yelled at by someone in the dungeon again.
又在地下城被不认识的人骂了…
People shouldn't abuse newbies!
反对霸凌新手！
You could say her feelings are clear
算是喜怒哀乐表现得很明显
or that she doesn't hide them.
也可以说是不会装模作样
I happen to think
我觉得
a straightforward girl like that would be perfect for you, Akito.
秋斗和这种女生应该很合拍
I won't accept some stranger!
瑠奈才不认可那种外人
You sound like a nosy sister-in-law.
你好像小姑一样
Not interested.
我没兴趣
Your adapter plug has melted.
电源接头融化了
A DAPPER BOAR?!
（接头？）
When did you buy this PC?
这台笔电是何时买的？
It was when I entered college, so…
刚上大学的时候…我想想…
TEXT FROM RUNA
（瑠奈传来新信息）
ALL GOING ACCORDING TO PLAN
（感觉气氛不错）
JUST FOR FUN
（享受游戏派）
Be still my heart!
开心
LOOKS GOOD, BUT THERE'S STILL DISTANCE.
（虽然不错，但还是有距离）
HELP THEM GET OVER THE HURDLE
（你帮忙加温他们的感情吧）
HELP THEM?
（帮什么忙？）
I PERSONALLY ENJOY A GOOD ROM-COM
（个人希望发展成恋爱喜剧）
Romantic comedies… you mean…
恋爱喜剧…我记得是…
WALKING IN DURING BATH, ACCIDENTAL FEEL,
（在浴室撞见）
LATE TO SCHOOL WITH TOAST IN MOUTH
（幸运吃到豆腐 快迟到时咬着吐司撞到人）
Like that?
这种发展？
You haven't ever cleaned your keyboard have you?
你从来没清过键盘吧？
Does it need that?
必须清吗？
-I think I see a stain. -No, don't look!
-好像有被什么泼过… -住手！不要看！
Another beautiful day.
今天也是个好天气啊
Akane!
茜
What's up? I'm almost finished.
怎么了？就快做好咯
Um…
我说啊
Are you planning to take a bath?
你现在有打算立刻去洗澡吗？
Not really.
没有啊
I'm cooking now. I'll take a bath tonight.
我正在做菜，晚上再洗澡
Yamada, will you take a bath?
山田，你要洗澡吗？
No.
不要
Who knows what she's thinking? Let's not ask.
搞不太懂，就别管她吧
Akane, can I have a slice of bread!
茜！给我一片吐司！
Go ahead!
你吃吧
If you eat now, will you have room for more?
吃这么多，会不会吃不下饭？
I'm making a rice omelet, you know.
我正在做蛋包饭
Don't worry. It's not for me.
别担心，反正不是瑠奈要吃的
NOT SURE HOW TO REACT
（太过突然，觉得纳闷）
GOT IT IN HER MOUTH,
（总之先让她咬了吐司）
BUT NO LONGER SURE SHE HAS THE RIGHT GENRE
（却不确定咬着吐司迟到 到底算不算恋爱喜剧而纳闷）
Why did you eat it?!
为什么要吃掉啊？
Why did you feed it to me?
为什么让我吃吐司？
Darn it, come over here!
真是的，你过来这里
-Hey, wait! -You need to get closer.
-等一下啦 -必须要靠近一点
-Don't push me! -So this can work out!
-这样很危险，别推啦 -才能幸运吃到豆腐
What are you…
别这样…
talking about?
子…
That hurt…
痛…
Huh? What comes next?
奇怪？接下来要怎么做？
-Stop this behavior at once-- -Ow…
-真是的，你够了哦 -好痛…
Yamada? Are you okay?
山田？怎么了？
Your hair hit my eye.
头发刺到我的眼睛…
Really? Oh, I'm sorry.
不会吧？抱歉
Are you okay? Is it stuck in your eye?
没事吧？跑进眼睛了？
That hurt…
好痛…
Show me!
让我看看
Which eye was it?
是哪只眼睛？
I'm…
我已经…
fine.
没事了
Oh no, I panicked and got right in his face.
糟糕，因为太心急抓住了他的脸
Maybe it bothered him?!
他该不会很讨厌这样吧？
I'm so sorry, Yamada!
山田，抱歉哦！
You apologize too, Runa!
瑠奈你也来道歉
I'm so… sorry!
对…对不起
I'll tie my hair up, okay?
我把头发束起来哦
-Um… -Yes?
-那个… -什么事？
I need some things from home.
我先暂时回家一趟
I didn't bring any tools with me.
因为我没有带任何需要的工具
Oh, but…
可是…
I'll be right back.
我马上回来
You mean there and back?
来回一趟很辛苦吧
-I don't want to take up-- -It's fine.
-这样太不好意思… -没事
I live close by.
反正很近
It was like he was running away.
他像逃跑似地离开了
You thought so too?
你果然也这么觉得？
It must have really bothered him.
看来他真的很讨厌那样吧
He really is uncomfortable around girls.
他真的很怕女生吧
I've done something awful.
对他做了过分的事了
Women with a light volume of hair
发量较少的女生
can tie it back
用这种发夹…
even with a pin like this.
就可以轻松固定好
Women with a heavy volume of hair…
发量较多的女生…
RUNA: HEAVY VOLUME, THICK TEXTURE
（发量多又粗）
…end up like this.
会变成这样
For women with heavy volume,
发量多的女生
even a ponytail is tough.
连绑马尾都很辛苦
MY ARM HURTS I'VE HAD ENOUGH
（手好酸，我不行了）
I'm jealous of your thin hair.
好羡慕茜的发量这么少
Isn't it better to have more?
发量多比较好吧？
Definitely not.
才没那回事
Young girls have all sorts of worries.
少女的烦恼没完没了